- Many organizations are excited
about the ways artificial intelligence
can take their business to the next level.
But they might not have a very clear sense
of which AI tools will help them get there.
Well-designed AI systems can help you
better interact with your customers or identify new markets.
These systems can predict your inventory
and make real-time decisions.
There's a huge amount of potential with this technology,
but with so many possibilities,
it can be hard to see the best place to start.
Hi, I'm Doug Rose, and this course takes a look
at popular tools and concepts
in artificial intelligence systems.
We'll start by exploring some high-level concepts,
such as machine learning, artificial neural networks,
deep learning, and natural language processing.
Then we'll look at the tools you'll need
to build these systems.
Some of these might come from software vendors,
while others might be open source tools
that allow you to build your own systems.
Whether you're an executive, director, project manager,
product manager, or software developer,
this course will help you benefit
from this powerful technology.
Your first AI products might determine
the entire course of your business,
so let's start figuring out what you need to know
to build or buy the best AI systems for your organization.