- Natural language generation
is a sophisticated way for artificial intelligence
to generate very natural-sounding text.
Now, I have a little bit of a confession to make.
I actually didn't write that first sentence.
It was written for me with the help
of a natural language generation, or NLG, application.
And while these applications can produce text
similar to what a human might write,
the process of writing is very different for an AI system.
The system doesn't write in the same way
that you might've learned in a Creative Writing course.
The computer sees writing as a data challenge,
and not a creative process.
An AI system looks for patterns in the data.
So in this case, the system finds the most common phrases
that match up to keywords.
For this sentence,
the AI system looked through millions of webpages
and matched words "natural language generation".
You can almost think of NLG
as a super-powered search engine.
The AI system searched for a phrase,
and then it searched deeper within those results.
Then it takes all that information
and reassembles it to closely match the text patterns
it came up with in the search results.
Afterwards, it goes through to make sure
that it's not an exact copy of the text and the results.
Now, the system just generated this one sentence,
but most people use this technology
to generate paragraphs, and even articles.
Right now, NLG works best for product reviews,
weather forecasts, and even news stories.
Natural language generation does especially well
when you have to combine data from different sources
and then present it to a wider audience.
The Associated Press uses NLG
to publish articles about a company's quarterly earnings.
These are short summaries
that come out about four times a year
to report how companies are performing
with their share price.
NLG works well here because you have data
from several different sources.
The NLG system combines these data sources
and adds some text to write a story.
That means that you'll get a quarterly earnings report
that sounds a lot like this.
"Microsoft had its third-quarter earnings report today,
and its stock price went up 5% in after-hours trading.
That's up 1% from last quarter,
and met forecasters' expectations.
The company said it was not affected
by supply chain issues with China."
So here you're combining the share price,
the expected share price,
and then how the shares were priced last quarter.
Then you'd combine that with relevant news.
Finally, you glue it together
with some appropriate words and transitions.
You've probably read several short stories written this way,
and not even realized that it was generated
in milliseconds by an AI system.
If you're thinking about using this technology
for your organization,
a good first step is to consider
the different data sources that you'd like to combine.
Maybe you'll create automated executive briefings,
or even short news stories.
Or as you'll see later, you can even use it
to better communicate with your customer.